Now we'll study metrics that we can
use to evaluate regression models.
现在我们来学习用于评估回归模型的指标
第一个称为平均绝对误差
The first one is called
mean absolute error.
在这个示例中 我们有一些点
In this example we have some points and
we have drawn a line
that fits these points.
并画了一条拟合这些点的线
现在 我们想检查这条直线的误差如何
Now we would like to check
how bad is this line?
A good way to do this is to
just add the absolute values
一个好方法就是将点到线的
距离的绝对值求和
of the distances from
the points to the line.
Mean absolute error is very
easy to calculate in Sklearn.
平均绝对误差在 Sklearn 中很容易计算
在这个示例中 我们要做的是创建一个线性回归分类器对象
What we do in this example is to create
a linear regression classifier object,
称为 classifier
called classifier.
然后用函数来拟合这条直线
Then we use the function
to fit the line.
现在 我们用 y 表示点
Now we can refer to the points as y, and
用 classifier.predict(X) 表示模型所作的预测
to the predictions made by
the model as classifier.predict(X).
We will call this guesses.
称之为 guesses
最后 平均绝对误差就用
And finally, the mean absolute
error is just calculated
平均绝对误差函数来计算
with the mean absolute error function.
平均绝对误差有一个问题
The mean absolute error has a problem,
which is that the absolute value
function is not differentiable.
即绝对值函数是不可微分的
这不利于我们使用诸如梯度下降等方法
And this may not be good if we want to
use methods such as grading dissent.
要解决这个问题 我们使用更常见的均方误差
To solve this problem, we use
the more common mean squared error.
对于此度量 我们添加点和线之间的距离
For this metric, we add the squares of
the distances between the points and
的平方
the line.
均方误差也很容易在 Sklearn 中计算
Mean square error is also very
easy to calculate in Sklearn,
只是现在 我们要使用 mean_squared_error 函数
except now we will use
the mean_squared_error function.
现在我们学习一个非常常见的回归度量 称为“R2 分数”
Now we will learn a very common
regression metric called R2 Score.
R2 Score is based on comparing our
model to the simplest possible model.
R2 分数通过将我们的模型与最简单的可能模型相比得出
那么思考一下
So let's think,
what is the simplest possible
model that fits a bunch of points?
拟合一堆点的最简单的可能模型是什么呢？
Well, a pretty simple one is just to
take the average of all the values and
那就是取所有值的平均值 然后
draw a horizontal line through them.
画一条穿过它们的水平直线
然后我们可以计算出这个模型的均方误差
And then we can calculate the mean
squared error for this model.
已知 简单模型的均方误差
We would hope that
the mean squared error for
大于线性回归模型的误差
the simple model is larger than
the error for a linear regression model.
The question is, how much larger?
那么问题是大多少？
Well, we can divide the error for
我们可以用线性回归模型的误差
the linear regression model by
the error for the simple model, and
除以简单模型的误差 然后
then subtract the result from 1,
and we will call this the R2 score.
用 1 减这个结果 我们称之为 R2 分数
如果这个模型不太好 这两个误差将很接近
If the model is not very good, then
the two errors should be similar and
而这个量应接近 1
this quantity here
should be close to one.
那么整个 R2 分数应接近 0
So the whole R2 score
should be close to 0.
如果模型较好 那么线性回归模型对的均方误差
If the model is good, then the mean
squared error for the linear regression
应比简单模型的均方误差小很多
model should be a lot smaller than the
mean squared error for the simple model.
那么这个比例就很小
Therefore this ratio shift is small, and
then the R2 square should
be very close to 1.
而 R2 分数将非常接近 1
总结来说 如果 R2 分数接近 1 模型就不错
In conclusion, if the R2 score is
close to 1, then the model is good.
And if it's close to zero,
then the model is not much
如果接近 0 那么模型
better than just guessing the average
of the values of the points.
基本相当于用点的平均值来猜测
R2 score is very simple to calculate
in Sklearn with the R2 score function.
使用 sklearn 中的 r2_score 函数 很容易计算 R2 分数
Here's a small example where we
calculated the R2 score between
这里是一个小示例 我们计算了
the true values in blue, and
the predicted values in green.
蓝色的真值和绿色的预测值之间的 R2 分数